Kibitou High School
Founder's Festival
Entrance
- 1 Year Ago -
ありがとうございまーす
Thank you very much!
Tonight is Christmas Eve.
〈（純一）今日はクリスマスイブ〉
〈学校では　にぎやかな創設祭が
行われていた〉
The busy Founder's Festival was taking place at school.
Miss Santa Contest
〈１年前のちょうど　この日〉
Right around this time last year...
My heart was broken.
〈僕は失恋した〉
〈そのせいでなんだろうけど〉
I'm not sure if it's because of that, but I don't like this time very much.
〈どうも　この時期が苦手だ〉
Kibitou High School
Founder's Festival
Entrance
I can't bring myself to join the fun.
〈楽しそうな雰囲気の中に
入っていくことができない〉
Are you going in, boss?
（梅原）寄ってかねえのか？　大将
Umehara.
梅原
I've been waiting this whole time for you to show up.
お前が来るのを
ずっと待ってたんだぜ
早く　ミス・サンタコンテスト
見に行こうぜ
Let's hurry up and go see the Miss Santa Contest.
Or we'll miss Morishima-senpai's turn!
森島先輩の出番　終わっちまうぞ
どうした？
What's wrong?
ごめん　梅原
Sorry, Umehara.
僕…
I...
そっか…→
I see.
クリスマスは　まだつらいか…
Christmas still hurts, huh?
じゃあ　今夜は寂しい一人もん同士
Well, why don't we lonely single men have a gaming and porn mag reading party at my place tonight?
俺んちで朝までゲーム大会アンド
お宝本鑑賞会といくか！？
えッ？
I don't have anything fancy like a Christmas cake or anything,
・（梅原）クリスマスケーキなんて
しゃれたもんは　ねえけど→
ちらし寿司なら
腹いっぱい食えるぞ→
but you can have as much sushi as you want.
Plus, instead of champagne, you can have some hot green tea!
それとシャンパン代わりの
熱いアガリもな
ハッハハ　いいな　それ
That sounds good.
56th Annual
Kibitou High School
Founder's Festival
Miss Santa Contest
Winner
・（司会）ミス・サンタコンテスト優勝は
今年も森島はるかさんで～す
And the winner of the Miss Santa Contest is...
Last year's winner, Morishima Haruka-kun!
Thanks!
（はるか）ありがとう～！
（フォークダンスの音楽）
Foun  der's
Festival
Plan ning
Committee
Founder's Festival
Planning Committee
（詞）来年は　きっと…
Next year for sure...
Kimi wa kimi no mama de
You just being you
君は君のままで
Boku wa boku no mama de
And me just being me
僕は僕のままで
Subete wakariaetara
If we could understand each other completely
全て分かり合えたら
UTW Presents
Amagami
SS
UTW Presents
Amagami
SS
Nando mo kisetsu wo kasaneta ne ano hi kara
The seasons have come and gone since that day
何度も季節を重ねたね　あの日から
Kyou made doumo arigatou
And even today, I remain so grateful
今日までどうもありがとう
Semai rojiura mezashi
We head towards a narrow back alley
狭い路地裏目指し
Shiroi iki ga odoru
As our white breaths dance in the air
白い息が踊る
Itai kurai nigitta te wo hiite
You hold me by the hand so hard it almost hurts
痛いくらい握った手をひいて
Kimi wa susunde yuku
And pull me with you as you walk on forward
君は進んでいく
Ima sugu kisu shitakatta
I wanted to kiss you right then
今すぐキスしたかった
Kakureta jihanki no ura
Hidden behind the vending machines
隠れた自販機の裏
Hanikande mitsumeatta
We shyly gazed at each other
ハニかんで見つめあった
Yasashii kimochi afureta
And I was overcome with kind feelings for you
優しいキモチ溢れた
Kimi wa kimi no mama de
You just being you
君は君のままで
Boku wa boku no mama de
And me just being me
僕は僕のままで
Subete wakariaeta nara
If we could understand each other completely
全て分かり合えたなら
Futari wa hitotsu da yo
The two of us would become one
２人は１つだよ
Donna chiisa na shiawase mo
No matter how small it may be
どんな小さな幸せも
Mitsukedaseru ki ga suru yo
We'll surely find happiness
見つけ出せる気がするよ
Yasashiku nareta no wa kimi no okage
I learned to be kind because of you
優しくなれたのは　君のおかげ
ふあ～
Morning, Junichi!
（梨穂子）おはよう　純一
おう　おはよ
Oh, morning.
Hasn't it gotten cold lately?
最近　寒くなってきたね
もう冬だからな
That's because it's winter now.
・（梨穂子）そうだね　冬だね
That's right, it's winter now...
Ayatsuji Tsukasa Arc
Chapter 1
Discovery
Obviously...
あたりまえだろ
・（梨穂子）ねえ　純一
ああ？
Hey, Junichi.
Huh?
・（梨穂子）クリスマスなんだけど
About Christmas...
Are you coming to the Founder's Festival this year?
今年は創設祭出る？
おッ…　どうだろう　分かんない
Let's see... I dunno.
何も予定がないなら
来ればいいのに
You should just come if you don't have anything else to do.
一応　学校行事だよ
After all, it's an important school event.
う～ん
The Tea Club is doing a store this year too, so come hang out!
・（梨穂子）今年も茶道部で　お店
出すと思うから→
遊びにきてよ　サービスするよ→
I'll even give you stuff!
Like tea or sweet sake.
お茶とか甘酒とか
お茶に甘酒ねえ
Tea and sweet sake, huh?
あんまり興味ない？
You're not really interested?
別に　そういうわけじゃないけど
That's not quite it...
〈あれから１年がたって
またクリスマスが近づいてきた〉
It's already been a year since then.
Christmas is approaching again.
〈相変わらず　苦手意識はあるけど
でも…〉
I have unpleasant feelings about it as usual...
But...
《・（梅原）来年は頑張ろうぜ》
《はあ？》
Let's try harder next year.
《・（梅原）今年は　もう
しょうがねえけど→》
I'm saying it's too bad this year, but let's find
girlfriends and have a fun Christmas Eve next year.
《来年こそ彼女を見つけて
楽しいイブを過ごそうって話だ》
《いつまでも
こうしていらんねえだろ？》
You can't stay like this forever.
I'll definitely find a girl!
《俺は必ず彼女を見つける！》
《来年　一人で寂しいイブを
過ごすことになっても》
So don't hate me if you end up spending Christmas Eve alone next year.
《俺を恨むなよ　へッ》
《ふんッ
その言葉そっくり返してやるよ》
I'll make you eat those words!
《ヘヘへ》
《ハハハ…》
That's right...
そうだったな
えッ？
うん　創設祭　今年は出てみるよ
Okay, I'll go to the Founder's Festival this year.
Really?  That's a relief.
ホント？　よかった～
えッ？
ううん　何でもない
Huh?
Ah, it's nothing!
梨穂子　転ぶぞ！
Rihoko, you're gonna fall over!
I'm fine!  Hurry up, Junichi!
・（梨穂子）平気だよ　純一も早く！
・（麻耶）みんなは　もう２年生
だから知ってると思うけど→
As juniors, you should all know this already.
Every year, on the birthday of our school's founder, December 24th,
本校では毎年
創設者の誕生日である１２月２４日に
学校の近隣住民　および
父兄の方との交流を目的とした
we hold a Founder's Festival with the aim of interacting with neighboring residents and family members.
創設祭が開催されます
そこで　今年の創設祭に向けて
On that note, we need to pick a committee
member from each class for this year's festival.
各クラスから実行委員を
選ばないといけないんだけど
誰か　立候補してくれる人
いないかしら？
Are there any volunteers?
・（麻耶）誰もいないの？
Nobody?
私が　やりましょうか？
I'll do it.
・（麻耶）絢辻さん　いいの？
Ayatsuji-san, are you sure?
はい
実行委員は去年もやりましたし
Yes.
I did it last year as well, and it
seems no one else is volunteering.
誰も立候補する人が
いないのでしたら
But you're already working as the class representative.
（麻耶）でもクラス委員との
掛け持ちは大変よ
大丈夫だと思います
I think I'll be fine.
I don't really have much work as class
representative around this time of year.
クラス委員の仕事は　この時期
もう　あまりありませんので
Even so, I still think having another person would be helpful.
それでも　やっぱり
もう一人くらい　いてくれた方が
いいと思うわ
Would anyone like to help Ayatsuji-san?
誰か　絢辻さんを手伝ってくれる
人は　いないかしら？
Well, I need to help at the restaurant...
（小声で）だから
俺は店の手伝いや…
Um...
あの！
えッ？
（薫）あッ？
あッ…
僕でよかったら
I'd like to help...
What's gotten into you, boss?
・（梅原）どうしちまったんだよ
大将？
創設祭だぞ
クリスマスイブだぞ！？
It's the Founder's Festival!
Christmas Eve!
And anyway, you're not the type to become a committee member!
だいたい　お前　実行委員なんて
タイプじゃないだろ？
あッ　まさか　絢辻さん狙いか？
Wait... are you going for Ayatsuji-san?
違うよ！
I'm not!
Do you have a fever or something?
熱でもあるんじゃないの？
あとは脈が弱くなってるとか
Maybe your pulse has weakened...
That's not it either.
そんなんじゃないって
You guys are jerks.
失敬だな　君達
Yeah, but still...
だって…　なあ？
ねえ
Right?
少し頑張ってみようと
思っただけだよ
I just figured I'd try a little harder.
頑張るって何を？
For what?
For Christmas.
クリスマスを
はあ？
いざとなったら　去年みたいに
I might change my mind like last year when the time comes.
気持が後ろ向きになっちゃう
かもしれないだろ？
So I figured I'll have to go even if I don't want to if I'm on the committee.
だから　実行委員になれば
イヤでも
当日　来なくちゃいけなくなるな
って思ったんだよ
はあ～　なるほどね
Ah, I get it.
I don't.
よく分かんないんだけど
Anyway, that's what it was.
とにかく　そういうことなんだ
橘君
絢辻さん
Tachibana-kun.
Ayatsuji-san.
まさか　橘君が立候補してくれる
なんて思わなかったわ
I didn't expect you to volunteer, Tachibana-kun.
I don't know how much help I'll be, but let's work together.
力になれるか
分からないけど　よろしくね
I did this last year too, so ask me if you have any questions.
私は去年も　やってるから
分からないことがあったら
聞いてね
Okay.
うん
・（梅原）頑張れよ
Best of luck.
I'll be cheering for you in my heart.
陰ながら応援してるぜ
陰ながらかよ
In your heart, huh?
Anyway, I'll be watching over you.
とりあえず　見守っててあげる
協力してよ
Help me instead.
Well, I'm planning to work on Christmas Eve.
・（薫）だってイブは
バイト入れる予定だし
入れるなよ
・（薫）いや　入れるね
You shouldn't.
Nope, I will.
Nii-nii, you're in the Founder's Festival committee now?
（美也）えッ　にぃに
創設祭の実行委員になったの？
まあね　それで早速　今日の放課後
Yeah.
We had our first meeting today after school.
初めての会合があったんだ
・（美也）どうだった？
How did it go?
In that case,
I'll take you on!
Well, my classmate Ayatsuji-san was chosen as the committee president.
Mumumu!
うちのクラスの絢辻さんが
実行委員長に選ばれてさ
She was nominated directly by last year's president.
前回の実行委員長から
直々に指名されたんだ
絢辻さんの人望の
あつさみたいなのを知ったよ
She knew that many look up to Ayatsuji-san.
はあ
So Nii-nii, are you and this Ayatsuji-san girl really close?
・（美也）で　にぃには　その
絢辻さんって人と仲いいの？
普通だと思うけど…　何で？
Not really.
Why?
にっしっし　だって　みゃー達の
クラスで何かやることになったら
Well, you could ask for favors if my class decides to do something!
ひいきしてもらえるかも
しれないじゃん？
Hey now, Ayatsuji-san isn't that kind of person.
あのな　絢辻さんは
そういうことする人じゃないの
じゃあ　にぃにでいいや
Then I guess you'll do, Nii-nii.
じゃあって何だよ　じゃあって
"Then"?  What do you mean, "then"?
・（美也）いいじゃん　いいじゃん
かわいい妹のためにさあ
Why not?  It's all for your cute little sister!
ムリだって
I said no.
Founder's Festival
Planning Committee Headquarters
（響）女子水泳部
おでん屋台で申請します
The Girl's Swim Club would like to run an Oden stall.
１年Ａ組で～す
We're from Class 1-A!
劇を予定してま～す
We'll be performing a play!
（琉璃子）茶道部だ　例年どおり→
Founder's Festival Activity Registration Form
Class/Club Name
Tea Club
Event
Tea Room (Tea, Snacks, Sweet Sake)
Location
The Tea Club garden
We're from the Tea Club.
Founder's Festival Activity Registration Form
Class/Club Name
Tea Club
Event
Tea Room (Tea, Snacks, Sweet Sake)
Location
The Tea Club garden
Founder's Festival Activity Registration Form
Class/Club Name
Tea Club
Event
Tea Room (Tea, Snacks, Sweet Sake)
Location
The Tea Club garden
Founder's Festival Activity Registration Form
Class/Club Name
Tea Club
Event
Tea Room (Tea, Snacks, Sweet Sake)
Location
The Tea Club garden
We're doing a simple tea party and selling sweet sake as usual.
簡単な茶会と
甘酒の販売を予定している
Huh?
あれ～？　純一
実行委員になったんだ
Junichi, you're on the committee.
Yeah.
まあね
それじゃあ　忙しくて
Does this mean you'll be too busy to come hang out on the day?
当日　遊びに来れないね
時間見て　顔出すようにするよ
I'll try to find some time to at least drop by.
（梨穂子）うん　待ってる
Okay, I'll be waiting!
Let's go, Rihocchi.
（琉璃子）行くよ　りほっち
All right, hang in there.
じゃあ　頑張ってね
うん
Yeah.
Is she your girlfriend, Tachibana-kun?
橘君の彼女？
ううん　ただの幼なじみだよ
Nah, she's just my childhood friend.
さてと　これで全部かな？
All right.
Is this all?
まだまだ
こんなもんじゃないわよ
Not even close.
There'll be plenty of people scrambling to hand it in on the day of the deadline.
締め切り当日になって
慌てて提出してくるところも
結構　あるんだから
I see.
そうなんだ
ええ
Yep.
それにしてもスゴイね　絢辻さんは
えッ？
You're pretty amazing though, Ayatsuji-san.
Huh?
Founder's Festival Activity Registration Form
Class/Club Name
Tea Club
Event
Tea Room (Tea, Snacks, Sweet Sake)
Location
こういう申請書とか
注意事項の書いてある紙とか
When did you make all these application forms and informational fliers?
いつの間に作ったの？
僕　全然知らなかったよ
I had no idea.
There was plenty of data from last year, so it wasn't too bad.
去年のデータが残っていたから
そんなに大変じゃなかったわ
What's more, you've almost finished handing them all out.
しかも　もう配り終えてるし
休み時間とか放課後を利用して
少しずつね
I handed them out slowly during breaks and after school.
I would've helped if you had asked.
言ってくれれば手伝ったのに
It was something I could handle alone.
一人で　できることだったから
あッ　そうだ
I know!
じゃあ　これから少し
手伝ってもらってもいいかな？
In that case, could you help me with something?
Sure!
もちろん！
Supply Room
去年
先輩から教えてもらったんだけど
My predecessor told me this last year,
ここのドアを開けるには
少しコツが必要なの
but there's a little trick to opening this door.
（鍵が開く）
So this is the supply room.
ここが資材倉庫か…
クリスマスツリーの電飾とか
It's where the lights for the Christmas tree and various things used in the Founder's Festival are stored.
創設祭で使う物を
しまっておく場所なの
基本的には
年に１回しか使われないわね
We technically only use them once a year.
あッ　閉めないで
Oh, don't close that.
ドアノブが少し壊れてて
部屋の中から開けられないの
The doorknob is a little broken, so the door can't be opened from the inside.
I see.
そうなんだ…　分かった
Got it.
Okay, please help me check the equipment here.
じゃあ　ここの備品チェックの手伝いを
お願いね
りょーかい
Gotcha.
It's really dusty in here though.
それにしても　ホコリっぽいなあ
少し換気しよう
Let's get some fresh air in here.
あッ？
あッ
ああ…
ごめん
Sorry.
う～ん
開かないか…
It won't open...
I don't think we can fit through there...
あそこから出るのもムリそうだし
ここから降りるのも
ちょっとなあ…
And we can't exactly get down from here.
はあ
I don't think there's any need to worry too much.
そんなに心配しなくても
多分　大丈夫よ
ここにいることは
他の実行委員に知らせてきたし
I let the other committee members know that we're here.
I'm sure someone will come soon.
きっと　そのうち　誰か来るわ
そうかなあ
You think so?
Even if nobody shows up and we have to spend the night here...
もし誰も来なくて
ここに泊まることになっても
Tachibana-kun, you'll protect me, right?
橘君が守ってくれるでしょ？
えッ？
ふふふ…　さあ　それより
仕事を始めちゃいましょう
All right, let's get to work.
Y-Yeah...
ああ　うッ　うん
ああ
橘君　どうかした？
What's wrong, Tachibana-kun?
う…　ううん　大丈夫
It's nothing, I'm fine.
うん？
By the way...
そういえばさ
うん？
どうして　絢辻さんは
実行委員をやることにしたの？
Why did you join the committee, Ayatsuji-san?
だって　ステキなことじゃない
Well, isn't it a wonderful thing?
みんなを楽しませる
お手伝いができるなんて
I can help bring happiness to so many people.
Hmm, that's true.
うん　確かにそうだね
What about you, Tachibana-kun?
橘君は？
えッ？
Huh?
Why did you join the committee?
どうして実行委員になったの？
I didn't think you were the type to.
そういうタイプじゃないと
思ってたんだけど
ハハハ
梅原にも同じこと　言われたよ
Umehara said the same thing.
So why?
ねえ　どうして？
I... thought I'd try a little harder.
少し
頑張ってみようかと思ったんだ
頑張る？
Try harder?
今まで　ちょっと消極的だったから
I've always been kinda unmotivated.
So I thought I'd change myself.
自分を変えてみようと思って
これは　その第一歩
And this is the first big step for that.
ふふ　ステキね
That's wonderful.
そんなことないよ
N-Not at all.
Ayatsuji-san, what kind of music do you listen to?
絢辻さんって
普段はどんな音楽を聴いてるの？
いきなり　どうしたの？
Why the sudden question?
何となく　聞いてみたくなって
I just kinda felt like asking.
そう　何となく
I see, you just felt like it...
う～ん
どんなって言われると難しいな
Well, that's a tricky question now that I think about it.
Why?
どうして？
I listen to a lot of different genres.
私　結構
いろんなジャンルを聴いたりするから
Like classical...
クラシックとか
Ｊ－ＰＯＰとか？
And J-pop?
うん　他にも…
Yeah, and other stuff like...
うん　全部　終わったわね
Okay.
That should be all.
Yeah.
だね　お疲れさま
Good job.
橘君こそ
You too, Tachibana-kun.
さて　結局　誰も来なかったね
Though...
Nobody came in the end, huh?
まさか　ホントにこのまま
泊まることになったりして
Don't tell me we're really gonna have to spend the night here...
Don't worry, the guard will make his rounds around here before that happens.
大丈夫よ　そうなる前に
警備員さんが見回りに来るから
あッ　そうか
Ah, I see.
・（美也）あッ　あったあった→
Ah, there it is!
Sae-chan, I found the supply room!
紗江ちゃん　ここだよ　資材倉庫！
この声は美也！
えッ？
That's Miya's voice!
I think that's my sister!
多分　妹だ！
Huh, that's weird.  It won't open.
・（美也）あれ？　おかしいな
開かないよ
（紗江）鍵が
閉まってるんじゃないかな？
Do you think it's locked?
Miya!
美也！
あッ　お兄ちゃん？
Onii-chan?  Why are you in there?
どうして
お兄ちゃんが中にいるの？
てゆーか
どうして鍵　閉めてんの？
And wait, why did you lock the door?
I didn't lock it, it got locked.
閉めてるんじゃない
閉まっちゃったんだ！
ドアノブを少し
下へ押し込むように回してみて
Try pushing down on the doorknob as you turn it.
It's the trick to opening this door.
（美也）えッ？
そのドアを開けるときのコツなの
L-Like this?
（美也）こ…　こうかな？
（鍵が開く）
It opened!
・（美也）あッ　開いた！
We're saved.
助かった～
・（美也）どうして
こんなところにいるの？→
Why are you in here?
Hide and seek?
隠れんぼ？
違うよ
No, it's committee work.
実行委員の仕事
We got locked in while doing that.
そしたら　閉じ込められたの
ありがとう　助かったわ
Thank you.  You really saved us.
Not at all, you're very welcome.
いえいえ　どういたしまして
それで　何か用か？
So what did you come here for?
Oh, that's right.  Our class wanted to use some costumes for our play.
あッ　そうそうウチのクラスの劇で
着ぐるみを使うことになって→
So we came to borrow some.
それを借りにきたの
貸し出し申請は　もう　してあるよ
We've already filled out a request form.
そうそう　これこれ！
Yes, this is it!
ウサギとサメ？
因幡の白ウサギ？
A rabbit and a shark?
Are you doing The White Hare of Inaba?
TL Note: The White Hare of Inaba is a classical Japanese folktale, in which a hare tricks some sharks into acting as a bridge for him.
ナイショだよ　にっししッ→
That's a secret!
Supply Room
さあ　行こう　紗江ちゃん
Let's go, Sae-chan.
O-Okay.
うッ　うん
あの…　ありがとうございました
Um... thank you very much.
資材整理が早速　役に立ったわね
そうだね
Sorting out all the equipment really helped, didn't it?
（ドアが閉まる）
Yeah.
（詞・純一）あッ
Supply Room
Miya!  Why did you shut the door?!
美也　何で閉めてくんだよ！
美也～
Miya!
Ah, I'm sorry!
・（美也）ああ　ごめんごめん
まったく　美也のヤツ
Geez, Miya's unbelievable.
うっふふ
ドキドキしちゃったわね
My heart was beating really fast.
Beating?  My heart almost flew out of my chest!
ドキドキっていうか
ハラハラしたよ
Huh?  Tsukasa-chan?
うふふ
（緑）あれ　詞ちゃん？→
Ah, it really is Tsukasa-chan.
あ～ッ　やっぱり詞ちゃんだ
You're out with a boy, huh?  I underestimated you.
男の子と一緒なんて
隅に置けないな
えッ…　だッ　誰？
W-Who's this?
My older sister.
私の姉よ
Nice to meet you.
初めまして
詞ちゃんの姉の絢辻緑です
I'm Tsukasa-chan's older sister, Ayatsuji Yukari.
I-I'm Ayatsuji-sa-
絢辻さ…　じゃなくて詞さんと
同じクラスの橘純一です
Uh, Tsukasa-san's classmate, Tachibana Junichi.
So you've been taking care of Tsukasa-chan... right?
いつも詞ちゃんが
お世話になって…　る？
N-Not at all.  More like she's taking care of me.
いえ　逆に僕が
お世話になってるくらいです
・（緑）そうなんだ～
I see.
What are you doing here?
どうして　こんなところにいるの？
うん？　お夕飯のお買い物
頼まれちゃって
I was asked to do the groceries for tonight's dinner.
そう　ごめんね　橘君
Oh.
Sorry, Tachibana-kun.
私　ちょっと用事を思い出して
I just remembered there's something I need to do.
ああ　そうなんだ
I see.
（緑）あん
また明日ね
See you tomorrow!
あッ　うん　また明日
Y-Yeah.  See you tomorrow.
Tsukasa-chan, you're walking too fast!
・（緑）詞ちゃん　歩くの速いよ～
うん？
（女生徒）どうなってるんですか
いったい！？→
What's going on here?!
Founder's Festival
Planning Committee Headquarters
ちゃんと
貸し出し申請書は出したのに
We turned in the request form like we were supposed to.
どうして他のクラスの分はあって
ウチのクラスの分は　ないんですか！？
So why do other classes get what they need and we don't?!
W-Well... I wonder why...
さッ　さあ…　どうしてだろうね？
Maybe there's a mistake...
何かの手違いかな？
Two power outlets aren't nearly enough!
電源タップが２個じゃ
足りないって！
Give us at least three!
せめて３個！　あと場所も
別のところがいいんだけど
I'd also like another location...
それを僕に言われても…
I'm not sure I can help you...
・（実行委員）先輩！
なッ　何？
Senpai!
W-What?
パンフレットの印刷部数って
何部ですか？
How many pamphlets were we supposed to print?
We just got a call from the printing press...
印刷所から問い合わせの
電話がきたんですけど
U-Um... let's see...
えッ？　えっと…
それは…
ダッ　ダメだ　絢辻さんじゃないと
手に負えないよ
I-I can't!
I can't handle this without Ayatsuji-san!
I think she said she'd be at the pool today...
今日は確か
プールにいるって言ってたっけ？
失礼しま～す
Excuse me.
・（恵子）絢辻さん　痛い　痛い
Ayatsuji-san, that hurts...
準備運動は
しっかり　やっておかないと
You need to do your warm up properly.
（恵子）絢辻さんの鬼～
何だ？
Ayatsuji-san, you monster...
What's this?
あら　橘君
Oh, Tachibana-kun.
What are you doing?
何してるの？
Supplementary swimming lessons.
水泳の補習よ
えッ？
For PE.
体育でね
水泳と陸上の補習をやってるの
I help with supplementary lessons for swimming and track.
The teacher is taking care of the track today...
先生は陸上の方を見ているから
私が代理として　こっち
So I'm acting as the instructor over here.
へえ　スゴイね
Wow, that's amazing.
水泳は得意じゃないんだけどね
Swimming isn't one of my strengths though.
What is it, Junichi?
何よ　純一
私達の水着姿でも拝みに来たの？
Did you come to stare at us in swimsuits?
バカ違うよ　絢辻さんを捜してたの
えッ？
Obviously not, idiot.
I was looking for Ayatsuji-san.
私を？
うん
Me?
Yeah.
There's a lot going on at the committee room.
実行委員の方で　いろいろあってさ
備品がないとか
電源タップがどうだとか
Like not enough equipment, what's happening with power outlets, how many copies of the pamphlets we need...
パンフレットの印刷部数は何部だとか…
そう　分かったわ
Okay, I see.
終わったら　すぐに
実行委員本部の方へ行くわね
I'll go straight to the committee room after I'm done here.
That'd really help.
助かるよ
気にしないで
Don't worry about it.
絢辻さんをサポートするために
実行委員になったんでしょ？
Didn't you become a committee
member to support Ayatsuji-san?
しっかりしなさいよ
Pull yourself together.
この　うるさいのは何で補習なの？
So why is this noisy girl having supplementary lessons?
I'm pretty sure she can swim.
泳げるはずだと思ったんだけど
棚町さんは休みが多かったから
Tanamachi-san skipped too many lessons.
I'm pretty sure you've been coming to school.
お前　ちゃんと学校に来てたよな？
I just don't like swimming.
水泳は嫌いなのよ
My hair gets all wet.
髪が　ぬれるから
Hey now...
おいおい
Well, Tachibana-kun.  I'll see you later.
じゃあ　橘君　また後で
Y-Yeah.
あッ　うん
She's the class rep, the committee president, and she even fills in for the teachers.
〈クラス委員もやって
実行委員もやって〉
〈さらに　先生の代理か〉
Ayatsuji-san really is amazing.
〈ホントにスゴイな　絢辻さん〉
Though...
〈それにしても…〉
The three of them are so full of life, aren't they?
・（はるか）３人とも
ピチピチしてるわね
そッ　そうですね
Y-Yes, you're right.
・（はるか）３人そろうと
相乗効果で→
And the effect multiplies with the three of them together...
さらに　こーッ
何ていうか　たまらないわね！
Ah, how do I say this... I just can't get enough!
はッ　はい…　って
Y-Yes.
W-What?!  M-Morishima-senpai?!
え～ッ　もッ　森島先輩！？
シッ
のぞいてるのがバレちゃうでしょ
Shh.  They'll find out we're peeping.
のッ　のぞいてるって…
What do you mean, peeping?
いつもなら
注意するところだけど→
Normally, I'd be warning you at this point...
But I understand your inability to withstand such charm.
あの魅力に　あらがえない気持も
分かるわ→
若いって素晴らしいわね～
It's so nice to be young!
えっと　あの…
Uh, um...
Come on, you need to hide.
ほら　隠れて　隠れて
そのままだと
向こうから見えちゃう
They'll see you if you stay there.
E-Excuse me!
しッ　失礼します！
Oh my, he left.
あらら　行っちゃった　まあいいか
Well, whatever.  I'll just take my time to enjoy the view by myself!
一人で　じ～っくり観賞しようっと
And just what are you enjoying?
・（響）何を観賞するって？
What do you think you're doing, Haruka?
（響）何をしてるの？　はるか
Uh, um... I was looking for you,
Hibiki-chan, and I didn't see you here...
あのね　響ちゃんを捜しにきたら
いないなあっと思って
今日は練習　休みなの？
You don't have practice today?
そうよ　先生が補習で使うって
言うから
Yeah.  The teacher said the pool would be used for supplementary lessons.
Okay, let's go back now that you've found me.
さあ　私も見つかったことだし
さっさと帰るわよ
響ちゃん　あと５分　５分だけ～！
Hibiki-chan!  Five more minutes, just five more!
Don't use excuses that sound like they're from someone who's half-asleep.
・（響）寝坊するときの言い訳
みたいなこと言わないの！
ふ～ッ　あと少しだ
Just a little more.
I'll go home once this is done.
これが終わったら帰ろう
それにしても　絢辻さんがいないと
やっぱり時間がかかっちゃうな
Though, this still takes forever to do without Ayatsuji-san.
あッ
Huh?  What's this?
うん？　何だ　これ？
手帳？
A notebook?
I wonder who dropped this...
誰かの落とし物かな？
Hopefully there's a name written somewhere...
どこかに名前でも書いてあれば…
Ah, it's finally over.
（薫）はあ～　やっと終わった
（恵子）私　もうヘトヘト～
I'm completely worn out.
はッ
スゴイな　予定が　ぎっしりだ
Wow.
Everything is really well planned out.
それに　きれいな字…
誰のだろう？
And the handwriting's really neat.  I wonder whose this is?
I'm pretty sure there'd normally be a name written at the back of something like this.
だいたい　こういうやつって
最後の方に
名前が書いてあるものだよな
（ドアが開く）
A-Ayatsuji-san?
あッ　絢辻さん
橘君…
Tachibana-kun.
Why are you still in a swimsuit?
どうしたの　そんな格好で？
何かあった？
What's the matter?
That... that notebook.
それ　その手帳…
あッ　もしかして絢辻さんの？
Is this yours, Ayatsuji-san?
That's good, I just picked it up.
よかった
今　ここで拾ったところなんだ
I see...
そう…
もしかして
中を見ちゃったりした？
Did you read it?
あッ　ごめん
どこかに名前があればって思って
Oh, sorry.
I was hoping I'd find a name in there, so just a little.
少しだけ
I see.
そう…
うッ！
あッ
Ayatsuji-san?
絢辻さん？
見ちゃったんだ…
So you read it.
えッ？
Hodou wo kazaru aoi Illumination
The blue illumination adorns the sidewalk
歩道を飾る　青いイルミネーション
Nigiwau hitogomi ni hitori tatazumu
And I stand alone in the swarming crowd
にぎわう人込みにひとりたたずむ
Koboresou na egao
Smiles peeking through
こぼれそうな笑顔
Yorisou koibitotachi
Lovers snuggling against each other
寄り添う恋人達
Ima no watashi ni wa subete ga
Everything to me now is so bright
今の私には全てが
Mabushikute mirenai no
That I cannot bear to look
まぶしくて見れないの
Dareka ni aisareru deshou ka
Will anyone love me?
誰かに愛されるでしょうか
Tsuyogari no oku ni kakureta
I'm hiding underneath a facade
強がりの奥に隠れた
Watashi ni kizuite yo
Please realize that
「わたし」に気付いてよ
Hontou ni jiyuu ni nareru deshou ka
Can I really become free?
本当に自由になれるでしょうか
Douka oshiete
Please tell me
どうか教えて
Fuyu no machi ni mayoikonda
Having lost her way in the winter town
冬の町に迷い込んだ
Samishige na tenshi ga nageku
The lonely angel sighs
さみしげな　天使が嘆く
Yasashiku
Gently
優しく
Preview
Next episode preview.
Junichi, what happened?  You look terrified.
K-Kaoru!
Aren't you a guy?  Pull yourself together!
Ayatsuji-san is...
Ayatsuji-san is...!
What about Ayatsuji-san?
Ah, so helping out with the committee work was tougher than you thought?
N-No, that's not it... it's...
Next episode: "Inner Side".
Next Episode
Inner Side
She has a much stricter side to her than you thought, huh?
She's an honest girl at heart though.
At heart...
At heart...!